<resources>
    <string name="app_name">EsutPUTME</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>

    <string name="tag_fragment_home">Home</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_middle">Middle</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_choose">Choose</string>

    <string name="tag_departments_list">Departments</string>


    <string name="tag_fragment_first">FirstFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_second">SecondFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_third">ThirdFragment</string>
    <string name="tag_fragment_fourth">FourthFragment</string>

    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="agreement">Agreement</string>

    <string name="nill">Nill</string>


    <!-- etc. -->

    <string name="English_comprehension_1"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p>\'You all know how friendly we are with Okperi. <em>Do you think that any Umuaro</em> man who goes to prison.</p>
    <p>\'You all know how friendly we are with Okperi. Do you think that any Umuaro man who goes to prison.</p>
        there will come back alive? But that apart, do you forget that this is the moon of planting? Do you want to
        grow this year\'s crops in the prison house in a land where your fathers owe a cow? I speak as your elder
        brother. I have travelled in Olu and I have travelled in Igbo, and I can tell you that there is no escape from
        the white man. He has come.

        <p>When suffering knocks at your door and you say there is no seat left for him, he tells you not to worry
        because he has brought his own stool. The white man is like that. Before any of you here was old enough
        to tie a cloth between the legs I saw with my own eyes what the white did to Abame. Then I knew there
        was no escape.</p>
        <p>As daylight chases away darkness so will the white man drive away all our customs. I know that as I say it
        now it passes by yours ears, but it will happen. The white man has power which comes from the true God
        and it burns like fire. This is the God about Whom we every eighth day… Unachukwu \'s opponents were
        now shouting that this was a meeting of an age group, that they had not assembled to join with him in
        chewing the seed of foolishness which they called their new religion.</p>

        <p>'We are talking about the white man's road’, said a voice above the others.
         <p>'Yes, we are talking about the white man's road, the roof and walls of a house falling, the ceiling is not left
        standing. The white man, the new religion, the soldiers, the new road - they are all part of the same thing.
        The white man has a gun, a machete,  <b>a bow and carries fire in his mouth.</b> He does not fight with one
        weapon alone.
       <i>(Taken from Chinua Achebe's Arrow of God)</i>

      <h4>1. 'There is no escape from the white man' in the passage means that the</h4>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="English_comprehension_2"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p>\Insects can be classified into fourteen separate groupings, or orders. Butterflies and moths belong to the
    Lepidoptera order. Lepidoptera means “scale wings”, from the Greek words “lepido” which means “scale” and “ptera” which
    means “wings”.</p>
    <p>Lepidoptera is one of the largest and most diverse insects\’ orders. The only order with more different species is
    coleopteran, that of beetles. So far, scientists have observed approximately 150,000 different species of
    butterflies and moths. Each species is distinguished by the unique arrangement, colour, and pattern of
    its scales. Worldwide, there are about 28,000 butterfly species. The rest of the species comprising
    Lepidoptera are species of moths. Though butterflies and moths both have scaled wings, there are some
    important differences between them. Butterflies are distinguished by their brightly coloured wings.
    Moths\’ wings are usually less bright. Butterflies are usually active during the day, while mothers are active at night. A butterfly\’s
    antennae are swollen at the tip, while a moth\’s antennae are feathery.</p>

        <h4>3. How many insect orders are there?</h4>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="English_comprehension_3"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p>In America, the first amendment to the Bill of \‘ights states, “Congress shall make no law.... abridging the freedom of speech.....” This
    amendment was passed to protect our right to express our opinions without fear. Yet, we must stop using the first
    amendment as a justification to say whatever we want, whenever we want. No speech is “free” when it has
    detrimental effect on the well-being of the others, the protection of our privacy, the safety of our borders, or
    the quality of our thinking.</p>
    <p>While censorship is not the way of this land, we must take into account the effect of musical lyrics that
    influence young listeners. How often do we find ourselves singing a tune or repeating a phrase from a
    song instinctively, without stopping to ponder the meaning of the words? When these words are
    <b><i>demeaning</i></b> to any group of people or when they incite violence, we are unknowingly repeating phrases of
    hate. How long does it take until those phrases become worn into our patterns of thought and we find
    ourselves believing the words we mindlessly hummed?</p>
        <h4>6. As used in the passage, the word demeaning most nearly means</h4>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="English_comprehension_4"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read each passage carefully and answer the questions that follow</h1>
    <p> Those who are familiar with it will tell you that Ludo, like human life itself, is a game both of chance and
    skill. You need skill in deciding how to make the most advantageous use of the figures, which turn up on
    the die when you cast it. Since each player has at least four alternative ways of using his figures, two
    players with equal luck may fare differently, depending on how cleverly each one uses his figures. The
    element of luck, again as in human life, plays a dominant role however. For no matter how skilful a player
    may be in using the figure he gets on the die, he has a slim chance of winning if he continually throws low
    figures. While a combination of ones and twos may be useful in checking the advance of one's opponents,
    it will not take one home fast enough to win. On the other hand, consistent throws of sixes and fives, with
    even the very minimum of skill will help a player to home all his four counters before any of the three
    other players, unless, of course, he has no idea of the game at all.</p>
    <p> </p>

        <h4>11. It is implied in the passage that two players may fare equally if they</h4>

    ]]></string>

    <string name="English_comprehension_5"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p>14. Read each passage carefully and answer the questions that follow.
    Farming is the most important aspect of agriculture that has attracted attention within the last few years.
    Agriculture has several other aspects like fishery, livestock and poultry. All these are also important in that
    they have to do with the production of food items which human beings consume for survival. In many
    parts of the world today, farming has been regarded as the mainstay of the economy. Crops such as cocoa,
    rubber and cotton have been produced in such commercial quantity that they are sold to other countries.
    Some countries have better comparative advantage in producing certain farm crops than other countries.</p>

    In these other countries, there is the need to spend a lot of money on agriculture, particularly farming.
    <p>Most farmers use outmoded tools. A lot of them have no place to store their crops, most of which are
    always destroyed by insects and pests before harvest time. All these have adverse effects on their
    productivity. The government can do a lot to help farmers. Farmers' co-operative societies can be
    encouraged and loans can be made available to farmers through government institutions like banks and
    finance corporations. Farmers can be taught how to build good storage structures for their produce. All
    these and a lot more can help to improve the conditions of farming in these countries.
    A lot of crops harvested are wasted because farmers
    </p>

    <h4>14. A lot of crops harvested are wasted because farmers</h4>
    ]]></string>

    <string name="English_comprehension_6"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p>15. Read each passage carefully and answer the questions that follow.
    It is customary nowadays among fashionable ladies and gentlemen to acquire strange and sometimes
    quaint clothes which are scarcely ever used: Sometimes it may be an approaching festival; sometimes a
    two hours\' ceremony and sometimes to honour a dead colleague - something triggers off the modern craze
    to sew new materials whose use does not outlast the moment of craze. And so, people who just occupy
    small apartments in their parents\' homes, or have rented one room in a densely-peopled house find that
    more than two-thirds of their rooms are filled with bongo trousers which they cannot wear, worn out jeans
    which stink, or specially made clothes for occasions that are not recurrent.</p>
    <p>Although plagued by the problem of school fees for their children, parents have had to swallow their own
    phlegm and humour of their children who need special clothes for important events. Newly employed
    youths soon find that their comrades are getting married, and new and special attire must be used to grace
    the occasion. University students see matriculation ceremonies or induction ceremonies into club
    membership as special reasons to make new attire which - you may be sure - they would not wear on
    another occasion that parallels the one for which these clothes were made.</p>
    <p>Medical doctors may soon find another cause for the incidence of high blood pressure among the youth.
    The desire to acquire new clothes is one strong possible cause, but a more subtle one which haunts like a
    ghost is the problem of choice of what to wear. The youths have so stuffed their apartments, wardrobes,
    drawers and trunks with so many clothes that the greatest problem they face is the choice of what to
    wear.</p>

     <h4>15. A suitable title for this passage is</h4>

    ]]></string>


    <string name="English_comprehension_7"><![CDATA[
    <h1> Read each passage carefully and answer the questions that follow.</h1>
    <p>It may be argued that museums as an institution and an agency for transmitting cultural heritage are an
    artificial creation, so far as objects are removed from their natural or proper environments and put into
    museums which are different environment altogether. However, it seems that museums themselves have
    come to be accepted and recognized as the best equipped institutions devised by man for the assemblage
    of cultural objects and their presentation and preservation for the present and future generations.</p>
    <p>The artificial character of museums is however being gradually transformed into a cultural reality. Thus,
    just as one goes to the theatre for plays and other performing arts; the mosque, the church or the shrine
    for worship; the library for the printed word; today, it is to the museum one goes to see evidence of man’s material outfit. For, no
    other institution or place so readily comes to mind as museums do when evidence of material culture is
    sought. Herein lies the importance of museums as cultural institutions and an agency for transmitting
    culture.
</p>

        <h4>16. Museums are an artificial creation because</h4>

    ]]></string>



    <string name="English_comprehension_8"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the passage carefully and answer the questions that follow it.</h1>
    <p>You would think that the common cold should be easy enough to study, but it is not so easy as it looks.
    Colds often seem to spread from one person to another, so it is often assumed that the cold must be
    infectious, but there are some puzzling observations which do not fit in with this theory. An investigator in
    Holland examined some eight thousand volunteers from different areas, and came to the conclusion that
    in each group the colds appeared at the same time. Transfer of infection from case to case could not
    account for that. Yet at the Common Cold Research Unit in Salisbury the infection theory has been tested
    out; two series of about two hundred people each were inoculated, one with salt water and the other with
    secretions from known cold victims. Only one of the salt-water group got a cold, compared with seventythree
    in the other group.</p>
    <p>In the British Medical Journal the other day, there was a report of a meeting \'The Common Cold-Fact and
    Fancy\', at which one of the speakers reported a study of cold made in Cirencester over the last five years.
    Three hundred and fifty volunteers had kept diary records of their colds and on an average each had seven
    every year, with an annual morbidity of seven days. So nearly one-fifth of our lives is spent in more or less
    misery, coughing and sneezing. Some widely held beliefs about the common cold have turned out not to
    be true. It seems that old people are just as liable to colds as the young. Sailors in isolated weather ship
    have just as many colds while on board and not in contact with colds as the young. Sailors in isolated
    weather ships have just as many colds while on board and not in contact with the outside world as when
    on shore. It is truism that common illnesses pose more problems than the rare. The rare disease is by
    comparison much easier to handle. There are not so many cases and all of them have been intensively
    studied. Someone has read up all the literature about the disease and published a digest of it. There will be
    more facts and fewer fancies.</p>


        <h4>The Cirencester volunteers kept a record of their colds through</h4>

    ]]></string>


    <string name="English_comprehension_9"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the passage carefully and answer the questions that follow it.</h1>
    <p>Whenever I have had to ask myself the question why I have not left this country for good, many answers
    rush to my mind, each striving to be recognized as being the most cogent. I am reminded of the popular
    slogan that \'this country belongs to us all\', for which reason every Nigerian must join hands in trying to
    salvage it. I try to dismiss the argument by reasoning that it is foolhardy attempting to lend a helping hand
    where one\'s services are apparently not required. Then I am reminded that if I left the country in a hurry
    just because of our political instability and economic hardships, my commitments to my family and
    extended family at home would suffer. I reply by saying that as soon as I got settled abroad; I would
    arrange for my family to join me. Other financial problems at home would be taken care of by my regular
    remittances. Would I then never think of going back Home in future? Not until the situation in the country
    improved considerably, I would answer. And who did I expect to carry on with the task of national
    rehabilitation when the likes of me are all out of the country? Those who messed up the country in the first
    place, I would argue. And so on. This dialogue of self has been going on for the last ten years or so;
    meanwhile, I am yet to leave the country.</p>
    <p>When I wonder how many people share my kind of mental experience, I realize that we must be very few.
    For not many have the slightest opportunity of absconding from the country; they do not have the place to
    run to nor do they have the means of escape. Even among the elite who consider this possibility, the
    uncertainty of a future outside their fatherland intimidates. And so we all end up staying and mumbling.</p>

        <h4>19. The expression 'each striving to be recognized as being the most cogent' means each</h4>

    ]]></string>


    <string name="English_comprehension_10"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following and answer question</h1>
    <p>It was part of her <b>nefarious</b> plot! Of that I had no doubt. She would slowly deprive me of my delicious
    slumber until finally, exhausted, I gave in to her wretched demands. She would claw her ways into my
    dreams, she could growl and complain, but no, I would not give in. I pulled the covers close over my head
    and rolled over. I was the stronger of we two. I was the determined one. I was the human, and she the
    beast. She must have understood my determination, for mercifully, the whining stopped. My breathing
    grew deeper and I returned to my wonderful sleep. Until moments later a crash awakened me. I bolted
    out of bed and there she was, in the kitchen guiltily lappily kitty treats off the floor. The mischievous beast
    had jumped onto the countertop and knocked the bag of food onto the floor. “Bad kitty!” I scolded,
    pushing her away from the mess of chow. But the sweet face, that little sandpaper tongue licking her
    chops somehow softened me.</p>


        <h4>20. The word “nefarious” as used in the first sentence in the passage means</h4>

    ]]></string>












    <string name="English">English</string>
    <string name="Mathematics">Mathematics</string>
    <string name="Current_Affairs">Current Affairs</string>
    <string name="Biology">Biology</string>
    <string name="Chemistry">Chemistry</string>
    <string name="Commerce">Commerce</string>
    <string name="Economics">Economics</string>
    <string name="Religious_Studies">Religious Studies</string>
    <string name="Geology">Geology</string>
    <string name="Government">Government</string>
    <string name="History">History</string>
    <string name="Literature">Literature</string>
    <string name="Physics">Physics</string>


    <!-- etc.


 <string name="English_comprehension_2"><![CDATA[
    <h1>Read the following passage and answer question</h1>
    <p> </p>
    <p> </p>

        <h4>3. How many insect orders are there?</h4>
        <p> </p>
        <p>

         <p>
       <i>()</i>

      <h4>1. 'There is no escape from the white man' in the passage means that the</h4>
    ]]></string>


    -->


</resources>

